Guide to the Charles McLean Andrews Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Peck, Epaphroditus 1860-1938
Penrose, Charles 1886-1958
Petrov, Vasili 1900-
Phelps, William Lyon 1865-1943
Philbrick, Francis Samuel 1876-
Phillips, James Duncan 1876-
Phillips, John Marshall 1905-1953
Pierson, George Wilson 1904-
Pottle, Emery Bemsley 1875-
Purdy, Lawson 1863-1959
Putnam, Bertha Haven 1872-
Putnam, Herbert, 1861-1955
Ragats, Lowell Joseph 1897-
Rait, Sir Robert Sangster 1874-1936
Randall, Daniel Richard 1864-1936
Read, Conyers 1881-1959
Reed, Edward Bliss 1872-1940
Reeves, William Peters 1865-1945
Reid, Adam 1808-1878
Rhoades, Charles James 1872-1954
Rife, Clarence White 1888-
Riggs, John Beverley 1918-
Robertson, Sir Charles Grant 1869-1948
Robinson, Chalfont, 1871-1946
Rollins, Carl Purrington 1880-1960
Root, Edwin Park 1861-1938
Root, Winifred Trexler 1879-1947
Rudin, Harry Rudolph 1898-
Ryden, George Herbert 1884-1941
St. John, Clara Hitchcock (Seymour) 1880-1958
Sarg, Tony, 1882-1942
Sargent, Elizabeth Collier 1881-
Sargent, Henry Bradford 1851-1927
Sawtelle, William Otis 1874-
Seymour, Charles 1885-1963
Seymour, George Dudley 1859-1945
Shipman, Arthur Leffingwell 1864-1937
Shorey, Paul 1857-1934
Shotwell, James Thomson 1874-
Shurtleff, Harold Robert 1883-1938
Siebert, Wilbur Henry 1866-
Simonds, Bruce 1895-
Sioussat, St. George Leakin 1878-
Skinner, Maud (Durbin)
Skinner, Otis 1858-1942
Slade, Caroline (McCormick) -1952
Smith, Abbott Emerson 1906-
Smith, Datus Clifford 1907-
Smith, Earl Terry 1876-1952
Smith, Ethel McCoy (Walker) 1872-1965
Smith, Jessie Willcox -1935
Smyth, Herbert Weir 1857-1937
Speer, Robert Elliott 1867-1947
Sprunt, James 1846-1924
Steiner, Walter Ralph 1870-1942
Stevens, Shepherd 1880-1962
Stone, Harlan Fiske 1872-1946
Swan, Thomas Walter 1877-
Swem, Earl Gregg 1870-
Taft, Eleanor K (Chase) -1961
Taft, Horace Dutton 1861-1943
Taft, William Howard, Pres. U. S. 1857-1930
Tatum, Edward Howland, 1908-
Tebeau, Charlton Watson 1904?-
Thacher, Thomas Day 1881-1950
Thomas, M Carey 1857-1935
Tinker, Chauncey Brewster 1876-1963
Towle, Dorothy (Siemering) 1906-
Turner, Edward Reymond 1881-1929
Tuttle, Henry Emerson 1890-1946
Updike, Daniel Berkeley 1860-1941
Vanamee, Grace (Davis) 1876-1946
Van Doren, Carl Clinton 1885-1950
Van Tyne, Claude Halstead 1869-1930
Van Zile, Edward Sims 1863-1931.
Ver Planck, Susan V (Walker)
Walcott, Frederic Collin 1869-1949
Walker, Annie Rose -1934
Walker, John Garland -1932
Wasson, Robert Gordon 1898-
Welch, Archibald Ashley 1859-1935
Welles, Lemuel Aiken 1870-
Wertenbaker, Thomas Jefferson 1879-1966
Wilder, Thornton Niven 1897-
Williams, George Clinton Fairchild 1857-1933
Williams, John Whitridge 1866-1931
Williams Stanley Thomas 1888-1956
Wing, Asa Shove 1850-1931
Winslow, Charles-Edward Amory 1877-1957
Wooley, Mary Emma 1863-1947
Yonge, Julian, Chandler 1879-
Young, Karl 1879-1943
Young, Stark 1881-
Young, Robert Fitzgibbon 1879-1960
Families; Historic buildings -- Conservation and restoration; History -- Sources -- Publishing; History -- Study and teaching; Masques; Mothers and daughters; Mothers and sons; Theater; Voyages and travels; Women -- Education; Women; East Asia -- Description and travel; Europe -- Description and travel; United States -- History -- Colonial period, ca. 1600-1775; Wethersfield (Conn.); Photoprints; Postcards; Scrapbooks; Authors; Educators; Historians; Lawyers; Adams, James Truslow, 1878-1949; Alexander, Everette Ralph; Andrews, Charles McLean, 1863-1943; Andrews, Elizabeth Byrne Williams, -1906; Andrews, Elizabeth Parkhill, 1868-; Andrews, Elizabeth Roberts; Andrews, Evangeline Walker; Andrews, John Williams, 1898-1975; Andrews, Julia Lincoln; Andrews, Mary Williams, 1865-1924; Andrews, William Given, 1835-1912; Andrews, W. W. (William Watson), 1810-1897; Asakawa, Kan'ichi, 1873-1948; Bates, Albert Carlos, 1865-1954; Skinner, Cornelia Otis, 1901-1979; Boyd, Julian P. (Julian Parks), 1903-1980; Brandt, Laura Marion Seymour Walker; Clark, Dora Mae; Connor, R. D. W. (Robert Digges Wimberly), 1878-1950; Day, George Parmly, 1876-1959; Dickinson, Jonathan, 1688-1747; Dutcher, George Matthew, 1874-; Eisenstadt, Abraham Seldin, 1920-; Farrand, Max, 1869-1945; Fisher, Samuel H. (Samuel Herbert), 1867-1957; Gipson, Lawrence Henry, 1880-1971; Greene, Evarts Boutell, 1870-1947; Harlan, Ethel Andrews Murphy, 1897-; Harlan, John M. (John Marshall), 1899-1971; Jameson, J. Franklin (John Franklin), 1859-1937; Jennings, Annie Burr, 1855-1939; Knollenberg, Bernhard, 1892-1973; Konkle, Burton Alva, 1861-1944; Labaree, Leonard Woods, 1897-1980; Lounsbury, Ralph Greenlee, 1896-; McLean, Mary Dyer Williams, 1822-1905; Morison, Samuel Eliot, 1887-1976; Morse, Jarvis Means, 1899-1974; Murphy, Henry Killam, 1877-1954; Newcomb, Eve Harlan, 1932-; Pargellis, Stanley McCrory, 1898-; Riggs, John Beverley, 1918-2006; Ryden, George Herbert, 1884-1941; Seymour, Charles, 1885-1963; Seymour, George Dudley, 1859-1945; Skinner, Maud Durbin, -1936; Smith, Ethel Walker, 1872-1865; Updike, Daniel Berkeley, 1860-1941; Andrews family; Walker family; Bryn Mawr College -- Alumni and alumnae; Bryn Mawr College -- Faculty; Colonial Williamsburg Foundation; Ethel Walker School (Simsbury, Conn.); Johns Hopkins University; National Society of Colonial Dames of America in the State of Connecticut; Taft School; Trinity College (Hartford, Conn.). Class of 1884; Yale University Press; Yale University -- Curricula -- History; Yale University -- Faculty
- CORRESPONDENCE, 1792-1956; Series I; 20; (49 boxes)
  Scope and Contents
  This series is arranged in chronological order.
  - 1792-1887 (Box 1, Folder 1-23)
  - 1888-1890 March (Box 2, Folder 24-35)
  - 1890 April-1891 (Box 3, Folder 36-44)
  - 1892-1893 July (Box 4, Folder 45-54)
  - 1893 August-1894 June (Box 5, Folder 55-62)
  - 1894 July-1895 (Box 6, Folder 63-73)
  - 1896-1897 August (Box 7, Folder 74-87)
  - 1897 September-1899 September (Box 8, Folder 88-101)
  - 1899 October-1902 June (Box 9, Folder 102-117)
  - 1902 July-1904 April (Box 10, Folder 118-130)
  - 1904 May-1905 August (Box 11, Folder 131-145)
  - 1905 September-1907 (Box 12, Folder 146-161)
  - 1908-1911 July 12 (Box 13, Folder 162-175)
  - 1911 July 13-1912 February (Box 14, Folder 176-185)
  - 1912 March-December (Box 15, Folder 186-194)
  - 1913-1914 March (Box 16, Folder 195-205)
  - 1914 April-1915 August (Box 17, Folder 206-216)
  - 1915 September-1916 (Box 18, Folder 217-226)
  - 1917-1918 (Box 19, Folder 227-239)
  - 1919-1921 July (Box 20, Folder 240-251)
  - 1921 August-1922 September (Box 21, Folder 252-262)
  - 1922 October-1924 April (Box 22, Folder 263-273)
  - 1924 May-1925 August (Box 23, Folder 274-284)
  - 1925 September-1926 August (Box 24, Folder 285-295)
  - 1926 September-1927 July (Box 25, Folder 296-305)
  - 1927 August-1928 August (Box 26, Folder 306-315)
  - 1928 September-1929 August (Box 27, Folder 316-327)
  - 1929 September-1930 April (Box 28, Folder 328-336)
  - 1930 May-December (Box 29, Folder 337-344)
  - 1931 January-August (Box 30, Folder 345-352)
  - 1931 September-1932 June (Box 31, Folder 353-362)
  - 1932 July-1933 March (Box 32, Folder 363-371)
  - 1933 April-December (Box 33, Folder 372-380)
  - 1934 January-1935 February (Box 34, Folder 381-392)
  - 1935 March-1936 April (Box 35, Folder 393-401)
  - 1936 May-1937 March (Box 36, Folder 402-411)
  - 1937 April-1938 January (Box 37, Folder 412-420)
  - 1938 February-July (Box 38, Folder 421-427)
  - 1938 July-December (Box 39, Folder 428-434)
  - 1939 January-November (Box 40, Folder 435-444)
  - 1939 December-1940 (Box 41, Folder 445-455)
  - 1941 January-1942 April (Box 42, Folder 456-463)
  - 1942 May-1943 December (Box 43, Folder 464-476)
  - Letters of condolence, 1943-1944
    General
    See: box 89, folders 975-976
  - 1944-1945 (Box 44, Folder 477-486)
  - 1946-1948 February (Box 45, Folder 487-498)
  - 1948 March-1950 February (Box 46, Folder 499-509)
  - 1950 March-1951 August (Box 47, Folder 510-519)
  - 1951 September-1953 July (Box 48, Folder 520-530)
  - 1953 August-1956 (Box 49, Folder 531-538)
- RESEARCH FILES, 1893-1943; Series II; 4.5; (13 boxes)
  This series is arranged in two sections: General and Topics. Each section is arranged in alphabetical order.
  - General
    - British Museum (Box 50, Folder 539)
    - British Public Record Office (Box 50, Folder 540)
    - Connecticut Archives I-VI (Box 50, Folder 541-543)
    - Gentlemen's Magazine (Box 50, Folder 544)
    - Georgia Gazette (Box 50, Folder 545)
    - Library of Congress
      - Notes (Box 50, Folder 546)
      - Collins mss. (Box 50, Folder 547)
      - Colonial money (Box 50, Folder 548)
      - Jones Thomas (Box 50, Folder 549)
        See also: box 53, folder 579
      - Molasses Act (Box 50, Folder 550)
      - Negroes (Box 50, Folder 551)
      - Piracy (Box 50, Folder 552)
      - Population (Box 50, Folder 553)
      - Staples (Box 50, Folder 554)
    - New York City Hall (Box 51, Folder 555)
    - New York Historical Society (Box 51, Folder 556)
    - New York Public Library
      - Bancroft transcripts (Box 51, Folder 557)
      - Beekman, Dongan, and others (Box 51, Folder 558)
      - Beverly letter book (Box 51, Folder 559)
      - Chalmers papers (Box 51, Folder 560)
      - Cuyler, Phillip: letterbook (Box 51, Folder 561)
      - Hawley, Kennebec, Jamaica, etc. (Box 51, Folder 562)
      - Journals (Box 51, Folder 563)
      - Smith, William papers (Box 51, Folder 564)
      - Smith of Nibley papers (Box 51, Folder 565)
      - Miscellaneous papers (Box 51, Folder 566)
    - North Carolina Historical Society (Box 51, Folder 567)
    - Pennsylvania Historical Society (Box 51, Folder 568)
    - Society for the Encouragement of Arts, Manufactures, and Commerce (Box 52, Folder 569)
    - South Carolina Gazette (Box 52, Folder 570-571)
    - South Carolina Historical Society (Box 52, Folder 572-573)
    - Universal Magazine of Knowledge and Pleasure (Box 52, Folder 574)
    - Virginia Gazette (Box 52, Folder 575)
    - Virginia Historical Society (Box 52, Folder 576)
    - Virginia State Library (Box 52, Folder 577)
    - Yale Library (Box 52, Folder 578)
    - Library of Congress: list of transcripts, 1906-1929 (Box 53, Folder 579)
  - Topics
    - Abercromby, James (Box 54, Folder 580)
    - Admiralty cases (Box 54, Folder 581-586)
    - Admiralty papers (Box 54, Folder 587)
    - Bill of 1701 (Box 54, Folder 588)
    - Blathwayt manuscripts (Box 54, Folder 589)
    - Board of Trade (Box 54, Folder 590)
    - British Colonial Administration I-IV (Box 54, Folder 591-594)
    - British Colonial Administration V-VII (Box 55, Folder 595-597)
    - Brock papers (Box 55, Folder 598)
    - Carlile proprietary (Box 55, Folder 599)
    - Colonial expansion (Box 55, Folder 600)
    - Colonial rivalry (Box 55, Folder 601)
    - Colonial union (Box 55, Folder 602)
    - Colonies
      - Barbadoes [sic] (Box 55, Folder 603)
      - Connecticut (Box 55, Folder 604)
      - Delaware (Box 55, Folder 605)
      - Maryland (Box 55, Folder 606)
      - Massachusetts (Box 55, Folder 607)
      - New Jersey (Box 55, Folder 608-609)
      - New York (Box 55, Folder 610)
      - North Carolina (Box 55, Folder 611)
      - Pennsylvania (Box 55, Folder 612)
      - Rhode Island (Box 55, Folder 613)
      - South Carolina (Box 55, Folder 614)
      - Virginia (Box 55, Folder 615)
    - Convict labor (Box 56, Folder 616)
    - Crevecoeur (Box 56, Folder 617)
    - Custom House (Box 56, Folder 618)
    - Ellesmere, Bridgewater (Box 56, Folder 619)
    - Ellestson, Roger Hope (Box 56, Folder 620)
    - Diplomatic (Box 56, Folder 621)
    - Gillams and the Hudson's Bay Company (Box 56, Folder 622)
    - H.M. main file access (Box 56, Folder 623)
    - Huntingdon family papers (Box 56, Folder 624)
    - Institutions: 18th century
      - Assemblies (Box 56, Folder 625)
      - Council (Box 56, Folder 626)
      - Governor (Box 56, Folder 627)
      - Mores of Government (Box 56, Folder 628)
      - Royal institutions (Box 56, Folder 629)
      - Trade in Connecticut and Pennsylvania (Box 56, Folder 630)
      - Trade in Maryland (Box 56, Folder 631)
      - Trade in New Jersey (Box 56, Folder 632)
      - King (Box 56, Folder 633)
    - Land system
      - General (Box 57, Folder 634)
      - Maryland (Box 57, Folder 635)
      - New England (Box 57, Folder 636)
      - New Jersey (Box 57, Folder 637)
      - New York I-III (Box 57, Folder 638-640)
      - North Carolina (Box 57, Folder 641)
      - Origin of town and county in America (Box 57, Folder 642)
      - Pennsylvania (Box 57, Folder 643)
      - Virginia (Box 57, Folder 644)
    - Loudoun papers (Box 57, Folder 645)
    - Marshalsea Court (Box 57, Folder 646-650)
    - Marshalsea Court (Box 58, Folder 651-652)
    - Naval stores (Box 58, Folder 653)
    - Non-importation agreement (Box 58, Folder 654)
    - Research notebooks
      - Bibliography and references (Box 58, Folder 655)
      - Board of Trade journal (Box 58, Folder 656)
      - General (Box 58, Folder 657-661)
      - General (Box 59, Folder 662-664)
      - Law notes (Box 59, Folder 665)
      - New York, Philadelphia, Rhode Island, South Carolina (Box 59, Folder 666)
      - New York (Box 59, Folder 667)
      - Rhode Island (Box 59, Folder 668)
      - South Carolina, Massachusetts supplemental (Box 59, Folder 669)
      - Treasury papers (Box 59, Folder 670)
    - Serle, Ambrose: diary (Box 60, Folder 671)
    - Stowe
      - Americana (Box 60, Folder 672)
      - Chandoes letters (Huntington Library) (Box 60, Folder 673)
      - Grenville (Box 60, Folder 674)
      - Royal African Company (Box 60, Folder 675)
      - Whatley Temple (Box 60, Folder 676)
    - Trade
      - General (Box 60, Folder 677)
      - Balance of trade; Medford chart (Box 60, Folder 678)
      - Bill of 1732 (Box 60, Folder 679)
      - Board of Trade (Box 60, Folder 680)
      - Carolinas (Box 60, Folder 681)
      - Competition (Box 60, Folder 682)
      - Colonies as a market (Box 60, Folder 683)
      - Illegal trade (Box 60, Folder 684)
      - Massachusetts Bay Colony (Box 60, Folder 685)
      - New England (Box 60, Folder 686-692)
      - Queen to governor of Maryland (Box 61, Folder 693)
      - Readjustments (Box 61, Folder 694)
      - Smuggling (Box 61, Folder 695)
      - Trade routes (Box 61, Folder 696)
      - West Indies trade (Box 61, Folder 697)
      - Wool (Box 61, Folder 698)
    - Treasury papers (Box 61, Folder 699)
    - Virginia (Box 61, Folder 700)
    - Miscellaneous notes (Box 62, Folder 701-705)
    - Photostats (Box 62, Folder 706-734)
      See also: box 69, folder 830
    - Printed matter (Box 62, Folder 735-737)
      See also: box 99, folder 1037
- WRITINGS, 1891-1952; Series III; 4.5; (14 boxes)
  This series is arranged in five sections: Colonial Period of American History, Dickinson's Journal, Walker Genealogy, Addresses and Articles, and Student Papers.
  - Colonial Period of American History, [ca. 1934-1938]
    - Vol. I (Box 63, Folder 738-758)
    - Vol. I (Box 64, Folder 759-763)
    - Vol. II (Box 65, Folder 764-775)
    - Vol. III (Box 66, Folder 776-782)
    - Vol. IV (Box 67, Folder 783-793)
    - Vol. IV (Box 68, Folder 794-804)
  - Dickinson's Journal, [ca. 1942-1947]
    - Typescript (Box 69, Folder 805-820)
    - Uncut printed copy (Box 69, Folder 821-826)
    - Research materials (Box 69, Folder 827-830)
      See also: box 73, folder 882
    - Research materials (Box 70, Folder 831-834)
    - Illustrations (Box 70, Folder 835-837)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 70, Folder 838-840)
    - Introduction (Box 71, Folder 841-842)
    - Appendix A (Box 71, Folder 843-849)
    - Appendix B (Box 71, Folder 850-857)
  - Walker Genealogy
    - Typescript, [ca. 1907] (Box 72, Folder 858-861)
    - Research material, 1891 (Box 72, Folder 862-869)
    - Correspondence, 1892-1952 (Box 72, Folder 870-872)
  - Addresses and Articles
    - "Anglo-French Commercial Rivalry, 1700-1750: The Western Phase, I, II.", 1915 (Box 73, Folder 873)
    - Berkeley celebrations, New Haven speech, undated (Box 73, Folder 874)
    - Bryn Mawr College speeches, [1943, n.d] (Box 73, Folder 875)
    - Cambridge History of the British Empire, Vol. I, [1929] (Box 73, Folder 876)
    - Chapter XIV: "The Government of the Empire 1660-1763", [1929] (Box 73, Folder 877)
    - Colonial Connecticut: notes, undated (Box 73, Folder 878)
    - Columbia University Department of History speech, undated (Box 73, Folder 879)
    - Connecticut history: part of speech, undated (Box 73, Folder 880)
    - Dedication of Jonathan Edwards Gateway, 1929 (Box 73, Folder 881)
    - Dickinson, Jonathan: notes, [ca. 1940-1947] (Box 73, Folder 882)
    - "Early log structures in Connecticut", undated (Box 73, Folder 883)
    - Education: notes and clippings, undated (Box 73, Folder 884)
    - "Fundamentals versus Ideals", undated (Box 73, Folder 885)
    - "Henry Whitfield: An Historical Estimate", [1937] (Box 73, Folder 886)
    - Institute speech, undated (Box 73, Folder 887)
    - "Introduction," The Quit-Rent System in the American Colonies, [1919] (Box 73, Folder 888)
    - "Isaac Allerton", undated (Box 73, Folder 889)
    - Jameson, John Franklin: drafts and proofs, undated (Box 73, Folder 890)
    - [Law Club or Lawn Club] and Center Church speech, undated (Box 73, Folder 891)
    - "On the Writing of Colonial History", [1944] (Box 73, Folder 892-893)
    - "Our Town Beginnings: A Commentary on Johnston's Connecticut", [1890s] (Box 73, Folder 894)
    - "Preservation of Historical Manuscripts", 1941 (Box 74, Folder 895)
    - "The Proprietary Element in Maryland During Colonial Times", 1929 (Box 74, Folder 896)
    - "The Quaker Press in London", undated (Box 74, Folder 897)
    - "The Royal Disallowance", [1914] (Box 74, Folder 898)
    - "Two Old New England Sea-Captains", undated (Box 74, Folder 899)
    - "Vice-Admiralty Courts in the Colonies", 1936 (Box 74, Folder 900)
    - "Virginia's Place in Colonial History", 1932 (Box 74, Folder 901)
    - Whitfield, Henry: notes, [1937] (Box 74, Folder 902-903)
    - Williamsburg lectures: I-VI, undated (Box 74, Folder 904)
    - Woodstock, Connecticut speech, 1940 (Box 74, Folder 905)
    - Yale University: speech to graduate students, undated (Box 74, Folder 906)
    - Miscellaneous, 1939, undated (Box 74, Folder 907)
  - Student Papers
    - A - Pa, [ca. 1920-1941] (Box 75, Folder 908-927)
    - Pe - unsigned, [ca. 1920-1931] (Box 76, Folder 928-932)
    - Examinations, 1919-1925 (Box 76, Folder 933)
- ALBUMS AND SCRAPBOOKS, 1860-1943; Series IV; 4.5; (8 boxes)
  This series is arranged in two sections: Albums and Scrapbooks. Each section is arranged in alphabetical order.
  - Albums
    - Family, 1897-1901 (Box 77, Folder 934)
    - World tour, 1913-1914 (Box 77, Folder 935)
    - Unidentified, undated (Box 78, Folder 936)
      See also: box 91, folder 986
    - Class album, [1884] (Box 78, Folder 937)
      See also: box 98, folder 1034
  - Scrapbooks
    - General
      - 1883-1909 (Box 79, Folder 938)
      - 1910-1925 (Box 80, Folder 939)
      - 1926-1937 (Box 81, Folder 940-942)
      - 1936-1943 (Box 82, Folder 943-944)
    - Printed material, 1888-1941 (Box 83, Folder 945-946)
    - Trip to England: correspondence, memorabilia, printed matter, 1896 (Box 84, Folder 947)
    - Trip to Holland, Germany, Switzerland, France, and England: correspondence, memorabilia, printed matter, 1898 (Box 84, Folder 948)
    - Andrews, William Given: scrapbook of British engravings, 1860 (Box 84, Folder 949)
- EVANGELINE W. ANDREWS PAPERS, 1863-1966; Series V; 5.75; (12 boxes)
  This series is arranged alphabetically by record type and/or topic.
  - Account book: record of investment income, 1945 (Box 85, Folder 950)
  - Alexander, Everette Ralph, 1913-1917 (Box 85, Folder 951-954)
  - British War Relief Society, Inc., 1941-1945 (Box 85, Folder 955)
  - Bryn Mawr College, 1897-1900 (Box 85, Folder 956)
  - Bryn Mawr College, 1901-1960, undated (Box 86, Folder 957-962)
  - Colonial Dames of America
    - General, 1923-1937 (Box 87, Folder 963)
    - Gunston Hall (George Mason house), Fairfax County, Virginia, 1936-1951, undated (Box 87, Folder 964-968)
    - Gunston Hall (George Mason house), Fairfax County, Virginia, 1936-1951, undated (Box 88, Folder 969-970)
    - Webb House, Wethersfield, Connecticut, 1919-1932 (Box 88, Folder 971)
  - Correspondence
    - No folders (Box 88, Folder 972-974)
    - Incoming: letters of condolence, 1943-1944 (Box 89, Folder 975-976)
    - Transcripts, 1923, 1930-1938 (Box 90, Folder 977-979)
  - East Dover, Vermont, 1932-1950, undated (Box 90, Folder 980)
  - Ethel Walker School, Simsbury, Connecticut, 1922 (Box 90, Folder 981)
  - No folder (Box 90, Folder 982)
  - Family papers
    - Andrews, John Williams, 1910-1950, undated (Box 90, Folder 983)
    - Harlan, Ethel Andrews Murphy, 1914-1951, undated (Box 90, Folder 984)
    - Harlan, Eve, [ca.1940] (Box 90, Folder 984)
    - Harlan, Richard D., 1919; 1928 (Box 90, Folder 984)
    - Smith, Ethel McCoyWalker, 1966 (Box 91, Folder 985)
    - [Smith, Ethel McCoy Walker?]: photograph album, 1883 (Box 91, Folder 986)
    - Walker, John Crawford, 1863-1875 (Box 91, Folder 987)
      See also: box 99, folder 1040
    - Walker, John Garland, 1932 (Box 91, Folder 987)
    - Unidentified: journal of travel in France, undated (Box 91, Folder 988)
  - Henry Whitfield State Historical Museum, Guilford, Connecticut, 1933-1952 (Box 91, Folder 989)
  - Masques, plays, pageants (other than Bryn Mawr), 1891-1933 (Box 92, Folder 990)
  - Memorabilia and printed material, 1895-1955,undated (Box 92, Folder 991)
  - Photographs: EWA, family classmates, miscellaneous, 1887-1927, undated (Box 92, Folder 992)
  - Postcards and some photographs, re: travel, [ca. 1902-1940]
    - Cambodia - Italy (Box 93, Folder 992)
    - Japan - U.S.A. (Box 94, Folder 992)
  - World tour
    - Charles McLean Andrews: notebooks and miscellanea, 1922-1927 (Box 95, Folder 993)
    - Correspondence, 1926-1927 (Box 95, Folder 994)
    - Itineraries, photographs, 1926-1927 (Box 95, Folder 995)
    - Memorabilia for journal, 1926-1927. (Box 95, Folder 996)
    - Writings, [ca.1927], undated (Box 95, Folder 997-998)
  - Writings
    - Essays and speeches, 1949-1952, undated (Box 95, Folder 999)
    - Journal, notes, 1916-1918 (Box 95, Folder 1000)
    - Masques and plays, 1909-1937, undated (Box 95, Folder 1001)
      See also: box 85, folders 956-962
      See also: box 92, folder 990
    - Notes and fragments, 1907-1953, undated (Box 96, Folder 1002)
    - Notes for Journal of a lady of Quality, 1929, undated (Box 96, Folder 1003)
    - Poems and stories, 1912-1949, undated (Box 96, Folder 1004)
    - Scripts and notes for "Chronicle of America" movie The Puritans, 1924, undated (Box 96, Folder 1005-1007)
  - Writings of others, 1916-1931, undated (Box 96, Folder 1008)
- MISCELLANEA, 1723-(1876-1967); Series VI; (3 boxes)
  This series is arranged in four sections: Organizational files, Biographical files, Photographs, and Memorabilia. Each section is arranged in alphabetical order, except Photographs, which is in chronological order.
  - Organizational files
    - American Historical Association, 1933-1942, undated (Box 97, Folder 1009-1011)
    - Colonial Williamsburg, 1932-1941 (Box 97, Folder 1012-1016)
    - Connecticut Tercentenary Commission, 1930-1935, undated (Box 97, Folder 1017-1024)
  - Biographical files
    - Andrews, Charles McLean: reminiscences to 1880, 1942 (Box 98, Folder 1025)
    - Andrews, Elizabeth Parkhill: reminiscences of CMA, undated (Box 98, Folder 1026)
    - Fisher, Irving N.: "The Charles McLean Andrews Collection," Yale Library Gazette, 1967 (Box 98, Folder 1027)
    - Jameson, John Franklin: copies of CMA's letters to Jameson re: Guides, 1906-1910 (Box 98, Folder 1028)